<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>m1ch43ly0.dev</title>
    <link>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Recent posts on ]]>m1ch43ly0.dev<![CDATA['s site.]]></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>© Michael Oliveira</copyright>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Marching Band</title>
      <link>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/12/remembering-marching-band/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/12/remembering-marching-band/</guid>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[My feelings and thoughts after my last high school marching band competition.]]>
        
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>November 23rd, 2025. WBA Grand Championships. My last day of high school marching band.</p>
<p>I started crying in Part 4, during the drum break. After my flugelhorn solo, I knelt on the sideline while the rest of the brass did their dance break. When they turned and looked toward me, seeing their smiling faces started the waterworks. Later, during the outro after Part 5 where my line ran one of the river tarps around the field, the tears would not stop. At the last hold, I could hear people from the color guard sobbing.</p>
<p>I remember our last moments on the field: feeling the emotions overcome me, trying and failing to maintain a smile for the audience as the tears flowed. Then, as we began pushing off the field, I remember yelling with joy, hugging my closest friends, and feeling a mixture of pride and sorrow. Proud of our band putting on the best performance we could have done. Sad that my high school marching band career was over.</p>
<p>Thinking about those final moments on the field, I remember the same events my freshman year. The same pride and sorrow. At the time, I did not think any other year would surpass it. That was my first year in marching band, and it left a lasting impression on me. My senior year, though, was even better.</p>
<p>I had a really close group of friends this year. We called ourselves the &ldquo;5 guys&rdquo;, and got a <em>tuff</em> photo at every competition. They are all high-achieving musicians and marchers, just like me, and it was great hanging out with them. Now, with marching season over, I hope we still stay close even though we don&rsquo;t have an activity bringing us together.</p>
<p>Life feels so strange without marching band. A feeling I haven&rsquo;t felt since freshman year. It&rsquo;s like a part of my life is empty; Wednesday evenings are occupied by homework and violin practice, not marching band. Saturdays are free for sleeping in, reading at the local bookstore, or taking a trip to the city, not marching band.</p>
<p>Looking back, I am so glad I did marching band. Some of my closest friendships came out of it. I made so many memories, documented on my camera roll and journal.</p>
<p>I will never have another high school marching band experience.</p>
<p>Last one, best one.</p>

<div class='callout callout-custom' style=''>
    <div class="callout-inner">
        
         <u>note to future self</u>
        <br />
        This is not the end! In 2 years, you will see me at the Lucas Oil Stadium in Indianapolis, for the 2027 DCI World Championships. :)

        
    </div>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music of Reflection</title>
      <link>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/11/music-of-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/11/music-of-reflection/</guid>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[How music can capture emotions and memories, with several examples.]]>
        
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="music-to-me">Music, to me.</h2>
<p><em>“Music is a universal language”</em> is a phrase I have heard endlessly, but which has always rung hollow.</p>
<p><em>How can I actually talk to someone with music?</em> young me wondered. <em>Does that mean I don’t need to learn English?</em></p>
<p>For me, a more accurate version is: <em>&ldquo;Music is a medium to express and share emotions&rdquo;</em>. Let me show what I mean.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="brahms-violin-sonata-no-2-in-a-major-op-100-1st-mvt">Brahms: Violin Sonata No. 2 in A Major, Op. 100, 1st mvt</h2>
<p>I first heard this piece played in a student recital at a violin summer festival I attended.</p>
<p>When I hear the opening piano part, I immediately feel a wave of nostalgia wash over me. That happened the first time I heard it, and every time since. It is a very interesting sensation, because it does not take me to a place or time I have been before. It just bathes me in the emotions of longing, melancholy, and a hint of joy.</p>
<p>Check out <a href="https://song.link/i/693110291">my favorite recording</a> of this piece by Itzhak Perlman and Vladimir Ashkenazy.</p>
<h2 id="just-the-two-of-us-grover-washington">Just the Two of Us (Grover Washington)</h2>
<p>This is the sound of the last month of sophomore year. That period of time was very special to me. It is hard to put into words, but it felt removed from the timeline of my life.</p>
<p>When I hear it, I remember walking around campus with my friends prior to the AP CSP exam. I remember stepping off of campus for the last time that year, feeling that my life was moving on. And I remember being in that bubble of time, enjoying the moment.</p>
<p>If my life was a film, that portion would have a slightly different tint that no other scene would share.</p>
<p>My jazz combo performed this song, as well as a <a href="https://song.link/us/i/1682357121">From the Start</a> and a few others, at my school&rsquo;s Senior Awards.</p>
<p>I listen to it whenever I want to be transported back to that vibe, or when it feels hard to keep living and looking forward.</p>
<p>Listen to this one <a href="https://song.link/i/391725517">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="suk-love-song-from-6-pieces-op-7">Suk: Love Song from 6 Pieces, Op. 7</h2>
<p>The title of the piece perfectly encompasses what I feel from this piece: love.</p>
<p>Just like the Brahms, I first heard this piece at a violin summer festival, performed as an encore by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vGp9rx6U2iQ">Ray Ushikubo</a>.</p>
<p>The warmth of D-flat major pairs incredibly with the melody of the first section. The feeling of love builds up and becomes so intense, entangled with the feeling of heartbreak: tender and raw. In the second section, it develops into a brighter and more wistful feeling, as if reminiscing on the happy memories with a past lover. It returns back to the first section, but with more movement in the piano accompaniment, as if they are starting to move on, with the heartbreak fading slowly. The piece ends with a final thought: that everything will be okay.</p>
<p>This piece got me through a lot of difficult times. It is my favorite piece of music, and I can feel myself going through all the emotions whenever I perform it. The way I feel after a performance of this piece is incomparable to any other.</p>
<p>Love. Hope. Comfort.</p>
<p>Take a listen to my <a href="https://song.link/i/1577946597">favorite recording</a> of this piece by Janine Jansen.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Each of these pieces marks a different chapter in my life, and different emotions I have felt throughout it: moments of longing, of connection, of healing. Music has a way of holding time still, of letting us return to who we once were, and who we are, and who we will become.</p>
<p>These three pieces are a small selection from my <em>reflection</em> playlist, where each piece or song carries a memory or emotion that is special to me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dream of Love and Joy</title>
      <link>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/11/a-dream-of-love-and-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelyodev.github.io/posts/2025/11/a-dream-of-love-and-joy/</guid>
      <description>
          <![CDATA[A recounting of a dream I had about love and joy, and the subsequent loss of it upon waking.]]>
        
      </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The memories are … fuzzy.</p>
<p>I can see her face, half-lit by the dream’s last streetlamp. I remember the clothes she wore, and the feeling of her wool coat brushing my wrist as we walked, hand in hand. I can feel the soft touch of her fingers on my cheek. I can picture the slight redness of her nose and cheeks from the cold, along with her beautiful smile. I can taste the meal we shared at the restaurant. I can hear the click of her camera, an old digital camera that looked like a Fujifilm.</p>
<p>I woke feeling joy. True joy. And love. The kind that inspires the butterflies in your stomach to flutter to their hearts’ content.</p>
<p>Then the details slipped, the memories faded, and the joy dissipated into the old familiar hush of my bedroom.</p>
<p>I searched my memories: no texts. No photos. No yesterday. It was just a dream.</p>
<p>All I was left with was the pain of emptiness and loneliness, a hopefulness for the happiness I could someday have, and an image of her face, slowly fading.</p>
<p>I do not know why God showed me what He did. All I know is that, through the pain and sadness, I look forward to the joy and love I will experience someday.</p>
<p>Someday.</p>
<p>Until then.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
